JUAN LUIS AZULA PASTOR

-Home Address: Av. San Felipe 695, Dpto 505, Jesús María, Lima, Perú -Mobile: 953-219-110 -Email: azula.juan@pucp.pe

PERSONAL PROFILE

Sociologist of PONTIFICAL CATHOLIC UNIVERSITY OF PERÚ (PUCP) and MSc in Social Science Research Methods of CARDIFF UNIVERSITY OF UNITED KINGDOM. I am a professional with initiative and perseverance. My interest topics are research methodology, applied statistics, organizational studies, sports sociology and sociology of technology.

EDUCATION

- Diploma of Specialization in Data Science for Social Sciences and Public Management
 I am currently studying the Diploma of Specialization in Data Science for Social Sciences and Public Management in the School of Social Sciences of Pontifical Catholic University of Perú (PUCP).
- MSc Social Science Research Methods (Sociology), Cardiff University.
 Training in Qualitative and Quantitative research methods.

2018-2019

- Licentiate in Sociology, Pontifical Catholic University of Perú (PUCP)
 Thesis Dissertation: Alcances y limitaciones de una experiencia de asociatividad. Acciones productivas y comerciales de pequeños productores algodoneros del Valle Pisco (Qualifying: Outstanding)
- Bachelor in Arts of Social Sciences, Pontifical Catholic University of Perú (PUCP)

2009-2013

Diploma in Applied Statistics, School of Engineering, Pontifical Catholic University of Perú (PUCP)
 Training in sampling, design of questionnaires and multivariate statistical analysis techniques

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

- Specialist, Pontifical Catholic University of Perú (PUCP).
 Research promotion directorate, Vice Rectorate for Research. Results and Impact Evaluation Specialist.
- Teaching, National Institute of Statistics and Informatics Course: Research Methodology

2021-ongoing

- Analyst, Ministry of Education of Perú
 Directorate of School Management DIGE (2019-2021), Directorate of educational services in rural areas DISER (2016-2017) and the Directorate Support of Decentralized Education Management DAGED (2015-2016). I was responsible of generating evidence (data) for decision making.
- Teaching Assistant, Pontifical Catholic University of Perú (PUCP), School of Social Sciences

 Experience of teaching the following courses: Statistics for Social Sciences I and II, Data Processing Workshop (use of qualitative software such Atlas ti and quantitative as SPSS, Stata and R). I was in charge of the preparation and presentation of practical sessions once a week during each semester.
- Research Assistant, Research Center of Pacific University Perú (CIUP)

2014-2015

OTHER WORK EXPERIENCE

Independent Consultant.

2013-2018

Ministry of Education, SASE Consultores, Pro Naturaleza, Center for Social, Economic, Political and Anthropological Research (CISEPA-PUCP), and others. I was responsible for information processing, creation of databases and information analysis.

Volunteer, Institute Bartolome de las Casas (IBC) – Perú.
 I worked with children in poverty situation, improving their academic skills in verbal and mathematical reasoning.

ACHIVEMENTS

- Responsible for giving the commencement address of Sociology School of Social Sciences 2013.
- Award of Good Practices in Educational Management in 2016 as part of the Directorate Support of Decentralized Education Management.

INTERESTS

I am interested in teaching at university level, quantitative and qualitative research. Also, I am great fan of sports like soccer, running and swimming. Nowadays, I seek to conduct research that consider sports activities as strategies of social inclusion and that contribute to the reduction of inequalities in society.

SOFTWARE KNOWLEDGE

PYTHON: Python Programming Language

R: The R Project for Statistical Computing – Intermediate

POWER BI: Power BI Desktop

SPSS: Statistical Package for Social Science – Advanced **CSPRO:** Census and Survey Processing System – Intermediate

STATA: Data Analysis and Statistical Software – Intermediate

ARCGIS: Georeferencing Software - Basic

REFERENCES

Phd. Robin Cavagnoud

Sociologist and demographer.

University Paris III, France. rcavagnoud@pucp.pe, 997068421

Phd. Hector Maletta

Economist.

Universidad de Buenos Aires (UBA), Argentina. hmaletta@gmail.com, 993151968